<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Stefano Pagliari - Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://stefanopagliari.net/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://stefanopagliari.net/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Political Economy of Financial Regulation</title>
      <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/financial_regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/financial_regulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A central theme explored in my research concerns understanding the drivers of regulatory reforms in the area of financial services, with a particular emphasis on the reforms triggered by the global financial crisis at the international level, as well as within key jurisdictions such as the US and EU. More specifically, some of the themes explored in my past research included the determinants and challenges of international regulatory cooperation after the financial crisis, EU-US transatlantic financial diplomacy, the regulation of derivatives markets, the political influence of the financial industry, and the attitude of individuals towards financial regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Financial Industry and the Interest Ecology of Finance</title>
      <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/interest_ecology_of_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/interest_ecology_of_finance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research into the political economy of international financial regulation following the global financial crisis has also led me to develop a research agenda focusing on the financial industry itself and its political power. While the political influence of the financial industry is a well-established theme within the literature, the financial industry does not operate in a vacuum. My work has provided new insights into understanding the interaction between the political power of financial industry and the constellation of actors that mobilise around the design of financial policies.  This work has detailed the extent to which the political advocacy of financial industry groups often benefit from the support of transnational financial coalitions  as well as other groups across the rest of the business community . It also revealed how significant obstacles remain to the political engagement in this area of those voices outside of the business community that tend to mobilize in opposition to the financial industry.  More recently, my work has also expanded beyond the analysis of firms and organisation, demonstrating that the attitudes of individuals towards financial reforms are influenced by the diffusion of financial-asset ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. International Financial Institutions</title>
      <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/international_financial_institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/international_financial_institutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research has investigated the role and drivers of different international financial institutions such as the Financial Stability Board and International Monetary Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Accountability after Financial Crises</title>
      <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/accountability_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/accountability_finance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The research with Iosif Kovras (University of Cyprus) explores the policies responses introduced after the financial crisis by national authorities and international financial institutioins to hold individuals accountable for illegal or unethical behaviors associated with the global financial crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Text as Data</title>
      <link>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/text_as_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stefanopagliari.net/project/text_as_data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my research I have explored new ways to leverage text-as-data approaches to investigate substantive political economy questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
